ARAF AL-JAMI

arafaljami
1331@gmail.com \diamond araf.aljami.me \diamond +8801755045141 \diamond Dhaka, Bangladesh

SUMMARY

Around 2 years of working experience as a software engineer, with a strong pursuit of problem solving. Hands on experience in building enterprise applications and maintaining best practices with OOD. Followed SOLID principles and design patterns to write clean, maintainable and adaptive code.

SKILLS

Languages: C#, Typescript, Javascript, C/C++

Specialties: .NET, .NET Core, Node js, Express, Web API, Git, IdentityServer4, Agile, Angular

Database and messaging: MongoDB, EF Core, MySQL, MassTransit, RabbitMQ, Mqtt, Azure Service Bus.

EDUCATION

Leading University, Sylhet

September 2014 - April 2019

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science and Engineering

EXPERIENCE

Shohoj Limited, Dhaka

Feb 2020 - Present

- Software Engineer, Backend
- · Refined the Nearest provider search, improving the performance up to 3x times.
- · Developed a service to provide, **Identity Access Management** service for 1+ million users.
- · Developed tools to migrate 1+ million users, from 12 different user store to 1 single consolidated user store.
- · Designed and developed, **User Access Management** system which consolidated user management for **6** different verticals to **1** single system.
- · Implemented a service, to aggregate location history data in friendly format for data science team.

Leading University, Sylhet

Jul 2020 - Present

Competitive Programming Trainer

- · Arranged and taken class on competitive programming topics, data structures, algorithms.
- · Arranged practice contest for students.

SELISE rockin' software, Dhaka

Nov 2018 - Jan 2020

Software Engineer

- · Used Angular, AngularJS to develop Single Page Applications
- · Used Dotnet Core technologies to develop REST API.
- · Worked on multiple projects and implemented business requirements for Selise Auditing and Certification Platform.

AWARDS & ACHIEVEMENTS

Onsite Competitive Programming Contests

September 2014 - Present

- \cdot 10th place (4th place University wise) out of **150** teams, at IUBAT ACM NCPC 2018. [link]
- · 16th place (8th place University wise) out of **120** teams, at MIST IUPC 2019

Online Competitive Programming Contests

September 2014 - Present

- · Active participant in online coding challenges on sites such as **TopCoder**, **Codeforces**.
- · Achieved Maximum Rating of 1982 (top 4%) in Codeforces. Handle: CLown1331. [link]
- · Achieved Maximum Rating of 1469 (Division 1) in TopCoder. Handle: CLown1331. [link]
- · Solved around 2800 problems in various online judges. [link]